# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Emmanuel Obiora Matthew H: +2348113419943 67/69 Odunfa Street, Lagos-Island, M: +2348132044517

Lagos State. E: <u>emmanuelobiora94@gmail.com</u>

### Professional research

My background lies in computer engineering. My research while in school focused primarily on electronic designs and development, its impact in the society and technology development at large.

**Information system and technology:** One of project I carried on technology is the design and development of an automated water dispenser using Arduino microcontroller coded in C++. This project involves the dispensation of water from an electronic device without touching or clicking on any button.

Furthermore, I did a course with Seamfix a software company with a good track record where I learnt Frontend development. During this program I was able to develop some websites that where fully responsive.

# **Academic qualifications**

Till- St. Gregory School of Music

Date Diploma

Music

2019 Enugu State University of Science and Technology

B. Engr.

Computer Engineering

2014 Cifman Institute of Technology and Management

NID

**Computer Software Engineering** 

2011 Police Secondary School Akure SSCE

2005 Dodan Barracks Primary School

**FSLC** 

#### **Certifications**

Till- SEAMFIX limited

Date Front End Design.

Software developer.

2021 National Youth Service Corps.

## **Professional Experience**

2022 – Seamfix.

Till date Frontend Developer

Training program

2021-2022 SS Peter and Paul nursery and primary school

**Teaching** 

**Duty**: Class-teacher

2020 – 2021 National Youth Service Corps

Teaching

June 2018 – NPF Microfinance Bank Plc.

November Internship

2018 <u>Dept.:</u> Marketing/Account

2014 – 2015 NPF Microfinance Bank Plc.

Internship

### **Extra-curricular experience**

2021 – 2022 Holy Cross Cathedral Lagos.

 I am serving as the assistant secretary to the Cathedral choir. My duties are to assist the secretary if absent or indispose. We manage the attendance of choristers, attend meetings and represent the choir where the need arises.

2017 - 2019 St. Albert the Great Catholic Chaplaincy, ESUT Enugu.

- During my stay at the chaplaincy I was privilege to oversee the affairs of a presidium in the legion of Mary as president and at the same time the president of the choir. In my final year I chairman the chaplaincy harvest and bazaar and with the help of other committee members the harvest was a success.
- My achievement ranged from the successful harvest and bazaar and leadership of two pius societies. The choir partakes in the 2019 film competition and came 3<sup>rd</sup> in 3 categories. Finally I was given three certificate of honor, this includes certificate from Nigeria federation of catholic students, certificate from legion of Mary, then lastly certificate from Angelic voice choir.

2015 St. Michael Catholic Church Lafiaji Lagos.

- I was the financial secretary of the 2015 harvest in my parish.
   During the period I partake in a leadership seminar/workshop
- At the end of the harvest period, we recorded success as intended project were completed and funds were generated for the parish affairs. A certificate of participation was given at the end of the workshop.

### **Skills**

2015

- o Computer proficiency in C++.
- o Computer proficiency in HTML and CSS
- o Computer proficiency in JavaScript, React, OOP
- Content creation.
- o Computer proficiency in Microsoft office packages.
- Good communication skills

### **Personality**

Gender: Male

Marital status: Single

Date of Birth: 3<sup>rd</sup> of DEC 1994

State of Origin: Enugu state

Religion: Christian

Language Spoken: English, Igbo, Yoruba

Nationality: Nigerian

#### Referees

Mrs. Ugwuja Virginia Civil Servant (Police children school) +2348053339510 Engr. Mrs. Oleka Chioma Lecturer (ESUT) +2348099456962